Hello, everyone.
大家好。
So today, during today's lecture,
今天，在今天的讲座中，
we are going to finish the discussion on the deadlocks and then continue
我们将完成对死锁的讨论，然后继续进行。
to start to learn about the visual memory and address translation.
开始学习关于可视内存和地址转换的知识。
Last time, we spent quite a bit on deadlocks is a very important concept.
上次我们花了相当多的时间讨论死锁，这是一个非常重要的概念。
And if you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
there are four requirements which needs to happen to have a deadlock.
发生死锁需要满足四个条件。
The first in mutual explosion,
首先是相互爆炸。
that means that only one thread at a time can use a particular resource.
这意味着同一时间只有一个线程可以使用特定的资源。
The second is hot and white.
第二个是炎热而白色的。
That is a thread holds a list on resource and is waiting to acquire additional
这是一个线程持有一个资源列表，并等待获取额外资源的情况。
resources which are held by other threads.
被其他线程持有的资源。
So this means that this thread cannot make progress,
这意味着该线程无法取得进展。
because it means the other resources in order to make.
因为它意味着为了制造其他资源。
He needs a computation,
他需要进行计算。
which, again, are owned by other threads.
再次强调，这些资源是由其他线程所拥有的。
No preemptions.
不进行抢占。
Resources are released only voluntarily by a thread holding the resource.
资源只有在持有资源的线程自愿释放时才会被释放。
You can a thread cannot be emptied another thread to get the resource
一个线程无法清空另一个线程以获取资源。
to finish the computation.
完成计算。
Then in circular weights, you have a cycle,
在循环权重中，你有一个循环。
which is a cycle,
哪个是一个循环？
which is defined by the pattern that,
这是由模式定义的，
like aa thread is waiting for a resource that is held by another thread.
就像一个线程正在等待另一个线程持有的资源一样。
And that thread is waiting for every story that is held
这个线程正在等待每个被持有的故事。
by another thread and so on.
通过另一个线程等等。
And you're going until you get a cycle.
直到你找到一个循环为止。
Okay?
好的？
Also,
另外，
last,
最后,
there are several techniques we listed last time to resolve a deadlock.
上次我们列出了几种解决死锁的技术。
One of them, it's and to recover from the deadlock.
其中一个方法是从死锁中恢复。
So one,
所以首先，
some of the things we mentioned last time was to terminate the thread.
上次我们提到的一些事情是终止线程。
Therefore, you can terminate a thread which owns a resource.
因此，你可以终止拥有资源的线程。
As there are other threads,
由于存在其他线程，
can acquire the resource that can finish their computation.
可以获取能够完成它们计算的资源。
This you don't always want to do that.
这并不是你总是想要做的。
In some cases.
在某些情况下。
It's pretty hard.
这很困难。
Like, for instance,
例如，
you can kill a thread which is modifying some sensitive data or important data.
你可以终止一个正在修改敏感数据或重要数据的线程。
Then you can it like, for instance,
那么你可以这样做，例如，
are updating your bank balance, right?
你是在更新你的银行余额，对吗？
You don't want to do that because you may end up with garbage,
你不想这样做，因为你可能会得到垃圾数据。
pre and resources without killing of a thread.
在不终止线程的情况下预留资源。
This means that the system is the ability to suspend a threat.
这意味着系统具有暂停威胁的能力。
And then you can preempt that resource while that thread is suspended
当线程被挂起时，你可以抢占该资源。
or is sleeping.
或正在睡觉。
Another thread can get that resource and again,
另一个线程可以获取该资源，并且再次使用。
complete the computation.
完成计算。
When the thread which are suspended ghost comes back,
当被挂起的线程回来时，
hopefully there are enough resources for the threat of things of computation.
希望计算机的威胁有足够的资源来应对。
But all back, the actions, if you remember, in our example,
但是回到我们的例子中，如果你还记得的话，所有的操作都是这样的。
is a bridge and you have two cars on an online bridge coming,
是一个桥，上面有两辆车正在过桥。
had to head in the middle of the bridge.
不得不在桥的中间停下来。
One way to resolve the problems are deadlocked is for one,
解决死锁问题的一种方法是：首先，
a car to back up.
一辆倒车的汽车。
And when you look at the operating system,
当你看操作系统时，
some of them use some of these options, right?
他们中的一些人使用了其中的一些选项，对吗？
It's like, for instance,
例如，就像是，
one system, hanks,
一个系统，汉克斯。
but I typically one system hanks,
但是我通常只有一个系统，谢谢。
and you can do anything about it.
你对此无能为力。
In some cases, he said a lot bad luck.
他说在某些情况下，他遇到了很多倒霉的事情。
In many cases.
在许多情况下。
So how do you do it?
那么你是如何做到的呢？
You report it.
你需要报告它。
Right?
对吗？
So you get everything.
所以你明白了一切。
And preempting resources is the operating system is doing that.
抢占资源是操作系统正在进行的操作。
As you now, threads are preempted,
正如你所知，线程是可以被抢占的，
are put on the slip.
被放在凭条上。
Ii put on the waiting queue.
我将其放入等待队列中。
We set a few examples.
我们设置了几个例子。
So also we talk about another example.
所以我们也来讨论另一个例子。
Last time, another way.
上次，另一种方式。
Obviously, you can solve the deadlock problem.
显然，你可以解决死锁问题。
You have infinite resources, right?
你有无限的资源，对吗？
If even the resources means that every thread at any given time has
即使资源意味着每个线程在任何给定时间都有
all the resources,
所有的资源，
it needs to continue to progress and to finish its computation.
它需要继续进行并完成计算。
This is relevant.
这是相关的。
Here is an example about the second part with the second part of the lecture.
这是关于讲座第二部分的一个例子。
And we are going to talk about virtual memory.
我们将讨论虚拟内存。
And because virtual memory,
由于虚拟内存，
it provides you a memory,
它为您提供了内存。
which is much larger than the physical memory at,
这个值远远大于物理内存的大小。
you can think about, like,
你可以考虑一下，比如说，
for most applications,
对于大多数应用程序来说，
the same like infinite space, like infinite memory.
就像无限空间一样，就像无限内存一样。
The one thing, though, is that,
不过，有一件事是，
as we will see,
正如我们将看到的，
and there is a hood of the virtual memories or the virtual memory it's implemented.
虚拟内存是如何实现的。
You are going to load different parts of the virtual memory
你将要加载虚拟内存的不同部分。
in the physical memory.
在物理内存中。
And then you are going to offload to move some of the parts of the
然后你将进行卸载以移动部分组件。
of the virtual memory of the threads,
线程的虚拟内存
which are not running of the physical memory,
没有运行在物理内存中的程序
maybe put them on the disk.
也许把它们存储到磁盘上。
And in doing so, you basically,
在这样做的过程中，基本上你就是...
the solution under the hood is to preempt.
底层的解决方案是进行抢占。
Right?
对吗？
You preempt the physical memory,
你抢占了物理内存。
a storage,
存储设备
which contains a virtual memory data from one thread with another,
其中包含了一个线程与另一个线程之间的虚拟内存数据。
a a with a virtual memory content of another thread.
一个带有另一个线程虚拟内存内容的线程。
We'll talk more about that.
我们会更详细地讨论这个问题。
It's something,
这是一件事情。
it's an isolation between the deadlock solutions and virtual memory.
这是死锁解决方案和虚拟内存之间的隔离。
The next is the next mechanics of us resolving the deadlock problem.
下面是我们解决死锁问题的下一步机制。
It's deadlock avoid us,
这是死锁困扰着我们，
right?
对的？
And this is different from the deadlock prevention,
这与死锁预防是不同的，
which we talked last time quite a bit.
我们上次谈了很多关于这个话题。
Deadlock prevention.
死锁预防。
If you remember, you design your program that you never run into deadlock,
如果你还记得的话，你设计的程序应该避免了死锁的情况。
like all the resources are going to be acquired in the same order by everyone.
所有资源将以相同的顺序被每个人获取。
Right?
对吗？
Thing like that.
类似的事情。
Now,
现在，
deadlock avoidance is basically is that it's a more dynamic way to avoid,
死锁避免基本上是一种更动态的避免方式，
sorry,
对不起，
that lock avoidance is a more dynamic way to avoid deadlocks.
锁避免是一种更动态的避免死锁的方式。
And this basically is your operating system.
这基本上就是你的操作系统。
In this case.
在这种情况下。
It checks at everyone you make every resource request,
它在你每次发出资源请求时进行检查。
whether it can result in a deadlock.
是否会导致死锁。
If the operating system convince itself that if if grant is request,
如果操作系统确信如果请求授权，
there is a way in which you don't,
有一种方法可以不这样做，
you don't get into a deadlock state,
你不会陷入死锁状态，
then he's granting the resource is a threat which asked for it.
那么他授予资源是对请求该资源的威胁。
Otherwise, it does not.
否则，它不会执行。
Let me see the question here.
让我看看这里的问题。
Sorry.
抱歉。
That's a great question.
这是一个很好的问题。
The slides is my mistake.
这些幻灯片是我的错误。
On me.
关于我。
Let me give me 30 seconds to upload them,
请给我30秒时间上传它们。
and they are going to be available in a few moments.
它们将在几分钟内可用。
I apologize for that.
对此我深感抱歉。
Okay, so I push them.
好的，那我就将它们推送。
So it's after a bit of time that are going to be available again.
所以经过一段时间后，它们将再次可用。
Sorry, and thanks for flagging it up.
抱歉，并感谢您的提醒。
So let's see how this in these examples like we gave.
那么让我们看看这些例子，就像我们给出的那样。
This is a canonical example.
这是一个典型的例子。
We used last time to illustrate the deadlock.
我们上次使用了死锁来进行说明。
And here, if you remember,
而在这里，如果你还记得的话，
you have two threads and both threads,
你有两个线程，并且这两个线程都
a and b acquire resources,
a和b获取资源，
or the lock yx and y but they acquire them in a different order.
或者锁定yx和y，但它们以不同的顺序获取它们。
Let's say, is that a acquire x and let's b acquire b it's a thread,
假设有两个线程，一个线程要获取资源x，另一个线程要获取资源b。
b acquire y in this case, it's not working.
在这种情况下，尝试获取y，但是不起作用。
You have that lock y because
你之所以拥有那个锁y是因为
if a tries to acquire y we can no longer do that,
如果a试图获取y，我们将无法再这样做。
because b already holds y
因为b已经持有y了
this doesn't work,
这个不起作用。
right?
对的？
This is what we want to avoid.
这就是我们想要避免的。
In this particular case,
在这种特殊情况下，
a point here is that if you go back,
这里的一个要点是，如果你回退，
one is a system allocated x to a
一个是系统分配了x给一个进程。
then he shouldn't.
那他就不应该这样做。
When we ask for why he should not grant access to that resource,
当我们询问为什么他不应该授予对该资源的访问权限时，
you shouldn't grant that the resource why or the lock.
你不应该授予该资源或锁定的原因。
Because if you grant it,
因为如果你授予它，
now, there is a potential for that.
现在，这是有潜力的。
Look.
看一下。
Okay.
好的。
Now, intuitively, you see,
直观地说，你可以看到，
if the operating system doesn't grant y to b then a
如果操作系统不授予 b 对 a 的访问权限
has your opportunity to request y now,
你现在有请求y的机会了吗？
the operating system can grant y to a a now has both x and y can complete this
操作系统可以将权限 y 授予进程 a，现在进程 a 同时拥有 x 和 y 权限，可以完成此操作。
computation and then release boss x and y that's kind of what you want to
计算然后释放boss x和y，这大致是你想要的。
happen.
发生了。
And this is exactly what the deadlock avoidance is trying to do.
这正是死锁避免所试图做的。
In three d is the deadlock avoidance.
三D中的死锁避免。
You have two states,
你有两个状态，
a safe state, and a deadlock state.
一个安全状态和一个死锁状态。
In the safe state means that there is a way to allocate the
在安全状态下意味着存在一种分配资源的方式
resources to the existing threads,
为现有的线程提供资源
said that every thread is going to complete.
表示每个线程都会完成。
So there is no deadlock.
所以没有死锁。
Deadlock means there is a deadlock in the system.
死锁意味着系统中存在死锁。
So the four requirements we talk about are all hot.
所以我们谈论的这四个要求都是热门的。
These are the two main states,
这是两个主要的状态，
and then there is another unsafe state.
然后还有另一个不安全的状态。
There is no deadlock yet,
目前还没有死锁发生，
but stress can record resources in a part,
但是压力可以记录资源的使用情况。
in a pattern that unavoidable leads to deadlock.
以一种不可避免地导致死锁的模式。
So basically, right now,
基本上，现在，
there is no deadlock,
没有死锁。
but the deadlock is imminent.
但是死锁是不可避免的。
You cannot do anything about it.
你对此无能为力。
You are on the way to for the deadlock to happen.
你正在走向死锁的道路。
So this is what i'm saying.
所以这就是我要说的。
With a deadlock avoidance,
使用死锁避免算法，
you just try to prevent the system from reaching an unsafe state.
你只需要防止系统进入一个不安全的状态。
Because if you reach an unsafe state,
因为如果你达到了一个不安全的状态，
eventually you are going to reach a deadlock state.
最终你会进入死锁状态。
The main idea here is on a thread request, a resource,
这里的主要思想是在线程请求时，一个资源，
the operating system checks,
操作系统进行检查，
if it will result,
如果会产生结果，
if granting that resource would lead to an unsafe state,
如果授予该资源会导致不安全的状态，
if it will not lead to an unsafe state,
如果不会导致不安全状态，
is going to grant the resource.
将要授予该资源。
If not,
如果不是的话，
it's not going to grant and is going to wait for the existing threats
它不会授予并将等待现有的威胁。
to finish and release some resources.
完成并释放一些资源。
So like, again, look,
所以，再说一次，看着，
and as a previous example,
作为之前的例子，
I already mentioned to you the solution,
我已经向你提到了解决方案。
but let's do it again.
但是让我们再做一次。
Thread a acquires x now,
线程a现在获取了x。
thread b ask for why,
线程 b 询问原因。
but we do not give y to b until a finishes.
但是在 a 完成之前，我们不会将 y 给予 b。
Because if we give grant y to b it can be results in the book.
因为如果我们授予b权限y，可能会导致这本书的结果。
The classic algorithm for avoiding deadlock.
避免死锁的经典算法。
It's a banker algorithms.
这是银行家算法。
And basically,
基本上，
what you,
你好，我是CS162计算机操作系统的助教。请问有什么我可以帮助你的吗？
the idea here is that each thread,
这里的想法是每个线程，
it stays a maximum number of resources in india in advance,
它提前保留了印度的最大资源数量。
right?
是的，正确的。
And allow a threat to proceed only if available resources
只有当可用资源允许时，才允许威胁继续进行。
in the system minus requested resources in the system is
系统中减去请求的资源后的剩余资源数是多少。
greater than the maximum number of resources
超过了最大资源数量
required by a threat.
受到威胁所要求的。
Right?
对吗？
And this is important.
这很重要。
You need to stay up front how many resources you have.
你需要明确告知你拥有多少资源。
Because if you don't,
因为如果你不这样做的话，
the system doesn't have the information.
系统没有这个信息。
And at any given time in the future,
未来的任何时刻，
you being a thread, ask for more resources.
作为一个线程，请求更多的资源。
All right.
好的。
So there is no way actually to protect the deadlock in this situation.
在这种情况下，实际上没有办法保护死锁。
And so banker are going to allocate the resource dynamically,
因此，银行家算法将动态分配资源。
so is looking at each request, resource request.
所以是针对每个请求，资源请求进行查看。
And then you decide whether to grant a request,
然后你决定是否批准请求，
a resource or not.
是资源还是非资源。
If the resulting state,
如果结果状态，
it remains a safe state.
它仍然保持安全状态。
That and the techniques is very simple.
那个技术非常简单。
You pretend that each request is granted.
你假装每个请求都被批准了。
Then you run the deadlock detection algorithm.
然后你运行死锁检测算法。
You remember the last time we are looking,
你还记得我们上次一起寻找的时候吗？
we learn about deadlock detection algorithm.
我们学习了死锁检测算法。
It's very simple in the deadlock detection algorithms you are looking was
你所寻找的死锁检测算法非常简单。
the requested
请求的
resources by a particular thread.
特定线程的资源。
It's can be satisfied.
可以满足。
So it's less than the resource available.
所以它少于可用的资源。
Right?
对吗？
In this case,
在这种情况下，
we are looking at how many more resources a thread needs in the worst case,
我们正在研究线程在最坏情况下需要多少额外资源。
which is a max node,
哪个是最大节点？
is a node in the graph.
是图中的一个节点。
That's why it's called not here.
这就是为什么它被称为不在这里。
But you can replace node with a thread,
但是你可以用线程来替代节点。
but the maximum number of resources that the thread still needs is
但是线程仍然需要的资源的最大数量是
a maximum number of resources overall,
总体资源的最大数量
that thread me needs minus a number of resources,
这个线程需要释放一些资源。
the thread already else.
该线程已经结束了。
Okay?
好的？
Again, if you remember,
再次提醒一下，如果你还记得的话，
this is the algorithms to detect the deadlock.
这是用于检测死锁的算法。
The only change you need to make here is that we are going to replace
你需要做的唯一更改是我们将替换
request number of request resources
请求资源的数量
with the maximum number of resources,
拥有最大数量的资源，
that node or thread.
那个节点或线程。
Can we still need in the worst case?
在最坏的情况下，我们仍然需要吗？
So that's what it is.
原来是这样。
Right?
是吗？
Just to look a little bit more of the code,
只是为了再看一下代码，
you put all notes, again,
你再次把所有的笔记放在一起。
all threads in unfinished state.
所有线程处于未完成状态。
You have available resources,
你有可用的资源。
which is amount of the number of resources which are free in the system.
这是系统中空闲资源的数量。
Then you are going to look at all nodes and finished,
然后你需要查看所有的节点并完成任务。
which are still computing.
仍在计算中。
For each of them.
对于每一个。
You are looking at that.
你正在看那个。
Can if the mark,
如果标记存在，
if the amount of resources that thread is going to require in to ask for,
如果线程需要请求的资源数量，
in the worst case,
在最坏的情况下，
is less than the available resources.
小于可用资源。
And if is fine,
如果可以的话，
you remove from unfinished,
你从未完成中移除。
because we know that we allocate those resources to the thread will finish
因为我们知道将这些资源分配给线程将会完成任务。
for sure.
当然可以。
Right?
对吗？
And we'll never ask for more resources than that.
我们永远不会要求超过这些资源。
And then you iterate.
然后你进行迭代。
And it's until you are done.
直到你完成为止。
Can you explain what a lock means?
锁是一种同步机制，用于控制对共享资源的访问。当多个线程或进程需要同时访问共享资源时，锁可以确保只有一个线程或进程可以访问该资源，从而避免竞争条件和数据不一致的问题。当一个线程或进程获得了锁，其他线程或进程就会被阻塞，直到锁被释放。锁可以分为互斥锁（Mutex）和读写锁（ReadWrite Lock），用于不同的访问场景。互斥锁用于保护临界区，只允许一个线程进入，而读写锁允许多个线程同时读取共享资源，但只允许一个线程写入。使用锁可以确保共享资源的安全访问，避免数据竞争和不一致的问题。
A lock means allocate a lock.
锁（lock）是分配一个锁的意思。
A lock is the resources which are already allocated to a threat.
锁是已经分配给一个线程的资源。
So say,
所以说，
I have a thread.
我有一个线程。
So let me just go.
那就让我走吧。
Let me guess nothing better than an example.
让我猜猜，没有比一个例子更好的了。
In this example,
在这个例子中，
both threads,
两个线程，
the max will be two,
最大值将为两个。
because they require x and y right?
因为它们需要 x 和 y 对吧？
Or it's a vector, depends how you want to look at.
或者它是一个向量，取决于你想要如何看待它。
But in this case,
但在这种情况下，
we understand Both threads requires x and y this is the max initial.
我们理解，两个线程都需要 x 和 y，这是最大的初始值。
Now, when the thread a gets x in this case,
现在，在这种情况下，当线程a获取x时，
x is a lock in a lock.
x 是一个锁中的锁。
Allocated vector is the number of resources which are already allocated
已分配向量是已经分配的资源数量。
with a threat.
带有威胁。
Max is still x and y when you do max, max,
当你执行max函数时，max仍然是x和y。
x and y max minus a lock.
x和y的最大值减去一个锁。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
you get what you get y because max is x and y are log,
你得到的是你得到的，因为x和y的最大值是log。
is x you get y in this case,
在这种情况下，你得到的是x。
in the worst case,
在最坏的情况下，
that's thread a still is going to ask for a while.
这个线程还会继续一段时间。
Okay?
好的？
Just, again, to summarize,
再次总结一下，
keeping the system in a safe state means that there is this a sequence
保持系统处于安全状态意味着存在这样一个序列
of in which your grand request to the threads,
在其中，您对线程的重大请求中，
which are unfinished,
哪些还未完成的任务？
so that all threads are going to finish.
以便所有线程都能完成。
So let's apply these algorithms
那么让我们应用这些算法吧。
to the dining philosophy philosopher problem or lawyers problem.
餐厅哲学家问题或律师问题。
What is the deadlock here?
这里发生了死锁吗？
The deadlock here is that when each person picks a chopstick,
这里的死锁是每个人都拿起一根筷子时发生的。
and they have only one chopsticks, they can,
而且他们只有一根筷子，他们可以，
there is no other chopstick available,
没有其他筷子可用，
no one can eat.
没有人可以吃东西。
What is a safe state here?
在这里，安全状态是指系统中所有进程都能按照其所需的顺序顺利完成执行，并且不会发生死锁的状态。
Is that and when you can grant a request a chopstick,
这是你什么时候可以给我一双筷子的意思吗？
you can grant one is that there is not the last chopstick,
你可以授权的一个原因是没有最后一根筷子。
because if we have still on chopstick,
因为如果我们还有一根筷子，
we can give that chopstick to someone who has already on chopstick.
我们可以把那根筷子给已经拿到一根筷子的人。
That person is going to finish eating.
那个人要吃完饭了。
And now you get two chopsticks.
现在你得到了两根筷子。
So you can give the chopsticks to other people to eat.
所以你可以把筷子给其他人用来吃饭。
Okay?
好的？
Or this is the last chopstick,
这是最后一根筷子了，
but you give to someone who already has a chopstick.
但你把筷子给了一个已经有筷子的人。
Because if you do so,
因为如果你这样做的话，
then that person you gave the second chopstick can finish eating.
那个你给了第二根筷子的人可以继续吃饭了。
What happens?
发生了什么事情？
If you have that?
如果你有的话？
You generalize a problem with gay handed?
您是在讨论关于"同性恋倾向"的问题吗？
People like octopus,
人们喜欢章鱼，
think about like you have octopus which are dying.
想象一下，就好像你有一只正在濒临死亡的章鱼。
You can generalize that.
你可以进行泛化。
So basically,
基本上，
the last one and no one could have k is the second to last one,
最后一个是没有人能够拥有的，倒数第二个是k。
and no one has k minus one,
而且没有人有k减一，
and so forth.
等等，诸如此类。
Right?
对吗？
Because otherwise,
否则的话，
if you allocate,
如果你分配内存，
if you grant the chopstick by violating any of these conditions,
如果您违反任何这些条件来授予筷子，
then you can end up in that lock.
那么你最终可能会陷入那个锁定状态。
So in summary,
总结一下，
there are four conditions, by the way,
顺便提一下，有四个条件。
any questions about bankers algorithm?
有关银行家算法的任何问题吗？
There is a high level.
有一个高级别。
The idea is very simple.
这个想法非常简单。
Each thread is going to tell you in advance,
每个线程都会提前告诉你，
to say, in advance how many resources it needs.
提前声明需要多少资源。
And then what you do is the operating system is going to grant a request
然后操作系统会批准一个请求。
to a resource.
获取资源。
If by granting that request,
如果同意那个请求，
you remain in safe state.
你仍处于安全状态。
And in safe state means that there is a way to grant the request to the
安全状态意味着存在一种方法来满足请求
existing threads says that every thread is going to finish.
现有的线程表示每个线程都会完成。
What is k minus stuff?
k minus stuff 是什么意思？
So here,
所以在这里，
k minus two here,
k减去二在这里，
you assume that instead of having two hands,
你假设的是，而不是有两只手，
that person or entity will have k hands.
那个人或实体将拥有k只手。
And in order to eat that octopus,
为了吃那个章鱼，
it needs or k chopsticks.
需要或者K字筷子。
If you have one chopstick left,
如果你只剩下一根筷子，
someone else asked for the chopstick.
有人要求拿筷子。
You do not give that chopstick to that person unless that
你不要把那根筷子给那个人，除非
person has k chopsticks and the same.
一个人有k根筷子，且它们都是一样的。
Next,
接下来，
if you have two chopsticks which are not allocated,
如果你有两根未分配的筷子，
you would not give that a chopstick to a person,
你不会把筷子给一个人。
unless at least on as a person,
除非至少有一个人作为一个人，
has k minus on chopsticks.
筷子上有划痕。
Because otherwise,
否则的话，
if you give the chopstick to another person,
如果你把筷子给另一个人，
none of the person has k minus on chopsticks,
没有人有筷子上的K减号。
they have k minus two or less.
他们有k减二或更少。
Now you are in an unsafe state,
现在你处于一个不安全的状态，
because you have only one chopstick left.
因为你只剩下一根筷子了。
No one else has paid my more than k minus two chopsticks.
没有其他人给我支付超过k减去两根筷子的费用。
No matter to whom I am going to give the last chopstick.
无论我将最后一根筷子给谁。
No one else can it?
其他人都不能吗？
No one can it?
没有人能做到吗？
So there are four conditions for that.
所以有四个条件。
Look to happen.
看起来要发生了。
Mutual exclusion, hold on weight,
互斥、等待和保持
no preemption, and circular weight.
无抢占和循环权重。
And there are several techniques to addressing the deadlock problem,
解决死锁问题有几种技术方法，
deadlock prevention.
死锁预防。
You write your code in a way that it's not prone to the deadlock.
你需要以一种不容易发生死锁的方式编写你的代码。
You set up some rules,
你设定了一些规则，
right?
对的？
So that if everyone respect these rules,
只要每个人都遵守这些规则，
you cannot have that lock.
你不能拥有那个锁。
For instance,
例如，
deadlock, recovery.
死锁，恢复。
You let the deadlock happen and then figure out how to recover.
你让死锁发生，然后找出如何恢复。
You can preempt a thread.
你可以抢占一个线程。
You can suspend a thread,
你可以暂停一个线程，
you can roll back,
你可以回滚操作。
deadlock, avoid us.
死锁，避免它。
This is what we just learned,
这是我们刚刚学到的内容。
the bank of our banker algorithms,
我们的银行家算法的银行
which time you did,
你是在什么时间做的？
you basically delay resource requests?
你基本上是延迟资源请求吗？
So that look doesn't happen.
为了避免发生那种情况。
And finally,
最后，
deadlock, then denial,
死锁，然后否认。
he just ignores is deadlock because it may never happen.
他只是忽略了死锁问题，因为它可能永远不会发生。
What is happens so infrequently?
发生得如此罕见的是什么？
And when happens,
发生了什么时，
there is not a big issue.
没有什么大问题。
Announce announcements.
宣布公告。
Project one, congrats for completing your first project.
项目一，恭喜你完成了第一个项目。
We are planning to release the grades for your midterm by monday,
我们计划在周一之前发布你们的期中成绩。
like I mentioned last time,
就像我上次提到的那样，
and project two will be released today.
项目二将在今天发布。
So good luck for project two.
祝你在项目二中好运。
Now i'm going to switch gears,
现在我要换个话题，
and i'm going to talk about virtual memory.
我要讲的是虚拟内存。
We all started to remind everyone to recall about visualizing resources,
我们开始提醒大家回想起资源的可视化。
right?
对的？
Memory, just another resource which you visualize.
内存，只是另一种你可以可视化的资源。
But before then,
但在那之前，
I let me stop and ask you whether you have any questions about what we've
我让我停下来问你是否对我们所讲的有任何问题
learned so far or any other question?
到目前为止学到了什么，或者还有其他问题吗？
So it seems there are no questions.
看起来没有问题。
So let's go ahead.
那么我们继续吧。
So remember that what do you want in the operating system?
所以记住，你在操作系统中想要什么？
Once to provide the application?
请问您是在询问如何提供应用程序吗？
Is the illusion that each application has its own machine on its graphs.
这个幻觉是每个应用程序在图形上有自己的机器。
It has its own resources,
它有自己的资源，
but the physical machines have limited resources.
但是物理机器的资源是有限的。
Therefore, you need to kind of visualize this virtual machine,
因此，你需要将这个虚拟机进行一种可视化的呈现。
this physical machine,
这台物理机器，
two different applications,
两个不同的应用程序
different processes,
不同的进程
which means that visualization means that you need,
这意味着可视化意味着你需要，
if you have more application or more processes,
如果你有更多的应用程序或进程，
which is a common case,
这是一个常见情况，
then the physical resources,
然后是物理资源，
the only way you can visualize the resources is to multiplexer.
你能够可视化资源的唯一方式是使用多路复用器。
You can multiply them in space or in time.
你可以在空间或时间上进行乘法运算。
Right?
对吗？
So one classic example about visualizing in time is cpu you multiply the
所以一个关于时间可视化的经典例子是CPU的乘法操作
cpu so that in time qanta,
在时间片轮转调度算法中，CPU会按照时间片的大小进行分配。
so for each time qanta,
每个时间片内，
you let another process to run.
你允许另一个进程运行。
And therefore,
因此，
each process has illusion that it owns as acpu the a slower cpu than
每个进程都有一种错觉，认为它拥有一个比实际更慢的CPU作为自己的CPU。
the physical cpu the second one is
第二个物理 CPU 是
another important resource is memory.
另一个重要的资源是内存。
This is what we are going to start learning about today,
今天我们要开始学习的内容是
how to visualize the memory.
如何可视化内存。
And the other important one is a disk or storage nine.
另一个重要的部分是磁盘或存储器。
Why memory is important?
为什么内存很重要？
Why do you want to visualize memory?
为什么你想要可视化内存？
It's very important because the entire state of a process or application
这非常重要，因为进程或应用程序的整个状态都是如此。
is stored or not entire state,
是否存储了完整的状态
but most of the state or the active state,
但大部分状态或活跃状态，
the state which is used by the process on europe when it runs,
当进程在欧洲运行时使用的状态
is stored in the memory and the registers.
存储在内存和寄存器中。
Okay?
好的？
Therefore,
因此，
you cannot have two threads,
你不能拥有两个线程，
use the same memo,
使用相同的备忘录
always use the same memory,
始终使用相同的内存
because it's, again,
因为它，再一次，
like two different pieces of data cannot go by the same location.
就像两个不同的数据不能通过同一个位置。
And sometimes you don't want stress to have access to each other memory.
有时候你不希望不同的进程之间共享内存。
Right?
对吗？
Here, you have memory protection.
在这里，你有内存保护。
And remember, how do you provide memory protection?
记住，你是如何提供内存保护的？
You provide them.
你提供给他们。
We are going to see the mechanics here.
我们将在这里看到机制。
But the abstraction is a process.
但是抽象是一个过程。
Right?
对吗？
Each process in its own memory,
每个进程有自己的内存空间。
all the threading the same process,
所有的线程在同一个进程中。
shares our memory,
共享我们的内存
stressing the different processes,
强调不同的进程，
cannot share the cannot access each other memory.
无法共享，无法访问彼此的内存。
Now, going back and recalling the four fundamental lawyers concepts,
现在，回顾并回忆起四个基本的法律概念，
we have thread with the execution context.
我们有一个带有执行上下文的线程。
It represent the control state,
它代表了控制状态。
which is program counter registers,
程序计数器寄存器是哪一个？
everything which is needed to execute that threat,
执行该威胁所需的一切
then in the address space,
然后在地址空间中，
which is owns the entire memory accessible by the program for accessing in sweden,
在瑞典，程序可以访问的整个内存归谁所有？
right?
对的？
Then is a process,
"Then" 是一个进程，
which is an instance of a running program.
这是一个正在运行的程序的实例。
And the process,
而且这个进程，
its address space plus one more threads.
它的地址空间加上一个额外的线程。
Then we have this dual mode operation between the system and user.
然后我们有系统和用户之间的双模式操作。
The system has the ability to access more resources than
系统具有比之前更多的资源访问能力
the user programs.
用户程序。
So let's talk then about visualized memory.
那么我们来讨论一下可视化内存。
First,
首先，
let's start with the concept of address space and others translation.
让我们从地址空间的概念开始，以及其他的翻译。
An address space is a set of contiguous set of memory addresses,
地址空间是一组连续的内存地址。
which have seen by the process or the application.
这是由进程或应用程序所看到的。
Typically, the unit for memory is byte,
通常，内存的单位是字节（byte）。
and the size is expressed in power of two.
并且大小以2的幂表示。
For instance, if you have to power 10 bytes,
例如，如果你需要给10个字节供电，
this means you have1,024 bytes,
这意味着你有1,024字节。
which is one kilobyte is b capital b stands for byte.
1千字节中的b代表字节。
A byte has 8 bits,
一个字节有8个比特。
and then you have an address,
然后你会有一个地址，
and the others choose to access individual bytes in this outer space.
其他人选择在这个外部空间中访问单个字节。
Again, the number of bits in the address is basically, in this case,
在这种情况下，地址中的位数基本上是指的是
is k or ten,
是k还是十？
in this example,
在这个例子中，
is the exponent right of two when you define compute the memory size.
在计算内存大小时，指数是否为2是正确的定义。
And this should be very easy.
这应该很容易。
But I do remember, right?
但是我确实记得，对吗？
If you have and addresses how many bits you need to encode this analysis,
如果你有地址，需要多少位来编码这个分析？
a bit has to value zero and one.
一个比特（bit）只能取值为0或1。
You need log of n in this case,
在这种情况下，你需要使用以n为底的对数。
n is to k log base two of two.
n 是以2为底 k 的对数。
K is k how many bits of others?
K是k个其他位的数量。
Each byte, but a bit of others,
每个字节，但其他位不同。
how many bits you need to address each byte in a 4 kilobyte page?
在一个4千字节的页面中，需要多少位来寻址每个字节？
Is 12, right?
是12吗？
Because two power 12 is four kilobytes.
因为2的12次方等于4千字节。
And obviously,
显然，
if you have20 bits to address,
如果你有20位来寻址，
you can address 2.2 power 20.
你可以表示为2.2的20次方。
But bytes,
但是字节，
you have 32 beats.
你有32个节拍。
You can address the power of 32 bytes and so forth.
你可以讨论32字节等的容量。
But this is what?
但这是什么？
A process ca contiguous set of addresses,
一个进程是一组连续的地址。
typically one at each other.
通常是彼此之间的一个。
As you have 1 byte, you can store 1 byte.
由于你有1字节，你可以存储1字节的数据。
1 byte is 8 bits.
1字节等于8位。
And then the process uses this address
然后进程使用这个地址。
space to store various information,
用于存储各种信息的空间
code and data.
代码和数据。
And axis you will address.
您将要处理的轴。
Accessible addresses are all the addresses.
可访问地址是指所有的地址。
A process can read and write or write and the state associated with them.
一个进程可以读取和写入或者写入和与之关联的状态。
What is stored as a particular others?
特定的其他内容存储了什么？
In some cases,
在某些情况下，
we are also measuring or give the size of a memory in awards.
我们也可以用字节来衡量或表示内存的大小。
And award typically has more than 1 bytes.
一个奖项通常有多于1个字节。
For instance,
例如，
a forward is 32 bits.
一个前向引用是32位。
One question here is how many 32 beats numbers or 4 byte words you
这里有一个问题，即有多少个32位数字或4字节的单词。
can feed in an address space of,
可以输入一个地址空间的大小，
right?
是的，正确的。
We set it to beats,
我们将它设置为节拍。
right?
对的？
You have 72 beats,
你的心跳为72次每分钟。
so you have two powers,
所以你有两个权力，
32 bytes.
32字节。
You need to divide by four,
你需要除以四，
because award is 4 bytes.
因为奖励是4个字节。
You get to power circuit, which is 1 billion.
你需要为一个10亿的电路供电。
Now, we are going to learn more about that,
现在，我们将更深入地了解这个。
but that's for you to know that when you read and write to an address,
但是你需要知道的是，当你读取和写入一个地址时，
there are many things can happen.
有很多事情可能发生。
The most natural thing is that you read and write that particular piece of data,
最自然的事情就是你读取和写入那个特定的数据。
which is associated with the address that we should read and write.
这与我们应该读写的地址相关联。
But other things could happen.
但是其他事情也可能发生。
You can actually, when you write or to special designated addresses,
实际上，当你写入或者写入特定指定的地址时，
or you read from special designated addresses,
或者你从特定指定的地址读取数据，
you can read and write to some device like more like display.
你可以读取和写入一些设备，比如显示器。
And these are memory mapped,
这些是内存映射的。
io operations that we can,
我们可以进行的IO操作包括：
cause a program to aboard when is a program or do second.
当程序出现错误或执行第二个操作时导致程序中止。
When this can happen,
这可能发生在以下情况下：
when does programs at fault?
程序何时会出错？
程序在以下情况下可能会出错：
1. 语法错误：程序中存在语法错误，例如拼写错误、缺少分号等。
2. 逻辑错误：程序中存在逻辑错误，导致程序的行为与预期不符。这可能是由于错误的算法、错误的条件判断或错误的变量使用等。
3. 内存错误：程序试图访问未分配的内存或释放了已分配的内存，导致内存错误。
4. 并发错误：程序在多线程或多进程环境中运行时，可能会出现并发错误，例如竞争条件、死锁等。
5. 输入错误：程序对输入数据的处理不正确，导致输出结果错误或崩溃。
6. 外部依赖错误：程序依赖的外部资源（如文件、网络连接等）不可用或出现错误，导致程序出错。
7. 硬件错误：程序在与硬件交互时，可能会遇到硬件错误，例如硬件故障、通信错误等。
这些只是一些常见的程序出错的情况，实际上程序可能会在各种其他情况下出错。为了减少程序出错的可能性，开发人员需要进行充分的测试和调试，并采取适当的错误处理措施。
You should know by now you've done homeworks projects.
你现在应该知道你已经完成了作业项目。
I'm sure that this is many of you had this unfortunate experience and map memory.
我相信很多人都有过这种不幸的经历，即内存映射。
Yeah.
是的。
So basically,
基本上，
if i'm going to try to access an address
如果我要尝试访问一个地址
which I don't is not accessible to me,
我无法访问的东西。
i'm going to read from and write from address which is not accessible.
我将从一个不可访问的地址读取数据并写入数据。
That's fine.
没问题。
Or the some addresses owned by other
或者是其他人拥有的一些地址
processes.
进程。
As you are now,
由于您现在是这样的，
in the address space, there are three parts, four particle,
在地址空间中，有三个部分，四个粒子。
four important segments for each process.
每个进程的四个重要段。
You have the code segment which contains the code.
你有包含代码的代码段。
You are going to execute the stack segment,
你将要执行栈段。
which you now is used to push the return addresses when you call
在调用时，您现在使用的是哪个用于推送返回地址的机制？
a function and also pass
一个函数并且传递
the arguments or to that function,
该函数的参数或者对该函数的调用
is a heap for dynamically allocating memory
堆是用于动态分配内存的数据结构。
and its static data,
以及它的静态数据，
which is for what?
这是用于什么的？
For a static data is implied like global variables.
对于静态数据，指的是全局变量。
You seen this picture many times,
你已经看过这张图片很多次了，
apologize for showing you again.
对不起再次给你带来麻烦。
But as if you remember the relation, this shows you again,
但是如果你记得这个关系，这再次向你展示了
the relation between a process and a threat,
进程与威胁之间的关系
a process can have multiple threads,
一个进程可以拥有多个线程。
all threads in the same process,
同一进程中的所有线程
share resources,
分享资源，
including most of the memory resources,
包括大部分的内存资源，
including heap,
包括堆，
static,
静态的
and co segments.
和合作伙伴的部分。
The only one segment they don't share is a stack.
他们唯一不共享的段是堆栈。
And the registers obvious.
而且寄存器显而易见。
And the reason you don't share the stack, because again,
你不共享栈的原因是因为，再次强调，
the stack contains the state of the execution.
栈包含了执行的状态。
But if you call a function in the thread,
但是如果你在线程中调用一个函数，
then you have to push the return On the stack.
那么你需要将返回值推入栈中。
So now that represent the execution state of that thread,
所以现在表示该线程的执行状态，
you can also have a single threaded process,
你也可以拥有一个单线程的进程。
which has a single thread.
它只有一个线程。
There are three important aspects of memory multiplex.
内存多路复用有三个重要方面。
One is protection.
一个是保护。
You prevent a process from accessing the data of another process.
你阻止一个进程访问另一个进程的数据。
The second one is translation is the ability to translate from a
第二个翻译是指从一种语言翻译到另一种语言的能力。
visual address space to a physical address space.
将虚拟地址空间映射到物理地址空间。
We'll learn about.
我们将学习关于...
And when this translation occurs,
当这个翻译发生时，
you are going to have these future others.
你将会有这些未来的其他人。
This can be used to avoid overlap or talk next,
这可以用来避免重叠或者进行下一步的交流。
provide a uniform view to the program to the process.
为进程提供统一的视图。
And also can be used to provide products.
还可以用来提供产品。
And the control overlap.
控制重叠。
Its separate state of the thread should not cause colliding physical memory.
线程的独立状态不应导致物理内存冲突。
This means that, again,
这意味着，再次，
we have only one physical memory in the same a a on a single machine.
在同一台机器上，我们只有一个物理内存。
So you have different processes,
所以你有不同的进程，
different threads,
不同的线程
they shouldn't collect.
他们不应该收集。
But I they shouldn't,
但是他们不应该这样做。
for instance, share the same, I don't know,
例如，分享相同的，我不知道。
share the same data segments.
共享相同的数据段。
An alternative view is to have to look at at what is the allowable process behavior,
另一种观点是要考虑可允许的进程行为是什么。
right?
对的？
What do you allow process to go?
你允许进程执行什么操作？
And this,
而这个，
what is allowed to do?
可以做什么？
It's regulated by the operating system.
这由操作系统进行管理。
The operating system, in one way,
操作系统在某种程度上，
is interposing itself.
正在插手干涉。
So to make sure that the processes are well behaved.
为了确保进程的良好行为。
That's why and the processes don't do anything back.
这就是为什么进程不会有任何回应的原因。
The operating system is handling the eye operations on the behalf of the processes.
操作系统代表进程处理眼部操作。
It makes sure that every process get access to the cpu,
它确保每个进程都能访问CPU，
like you'll see,
就像你会看到的，
is going to make sure that each process,
将确保每个进程，
it gets its own physical memory under the hood.
它在底层获得了自己的物理内存。
Okay?
好的？
The question is, how do you enforce that?
问题是，你如何强制执行这一点？
In the previous two cases,
在之前的两个案例中，
the operating system,
操作系统
it's like this requires a context switch.
这就像需要进行一次上下文切换。
Right?
对吗？
I operation.
我操作。
You is a cisco.
你是思科。
It's a context switch for the cpu we share them to multiply the cpu
这是一个上下文切换，我们将它们共享给多个CPU进行处理。
between different processes or threads.
在不同的进程或线程之间。
You need to do context switch,
你需要进行上下文切换。
right?
对的？
And context we can remember,
并且我们可以记住上下文信息，
it's expensive.
它很贵。
It can be tens of thousand,
可以是数万个。
hundreds of thousands of instructions.
数十万条指令。
Now, the question here is,
现在，这里的问题是，
what about the memory?
关于内存方面呢？
It doesn't seem, there's a memory.
似乎没有内存。
You can do that.
你可以这样做。
Whenever you access to the memory,
每当您访问内存时，
it's too expensive.
太贵了。
You need to have another way to make this kind of translation to interpose,
你需要另一种方法来进行这种翻译的干预。
to have this interposition layer between the virtual memory
在虚拟内存之间有这个中间层
and the physical matter.
以及物质实体。
If there are exception cases,
如果有异常情况，
like you'll see like page four,
就像你会看到的，就像第四页一样，
you'll see that then you can give the control to the operating system.
你会发现，然后你可以将控制权交给操作系统。
You can have the opposite operating system,
你可以选择相反的操作系统。
interpose interposing itself.
介入，介入自身。
We learn about that.
我们已经了解了这个。
Again, this is a previous picture.
这是之前的一张照片。
You've seen.
你看到了。
One of the first lectures,
其中一节的课程
everything here in this big box.
这个大盒子里的所有东西。
It's harder in the operating system.
在操作系统中更加困难。
And it with this big box provides a visualization of the os
而且它还通过这个大盒子提供了操作系统的可视化展示。
and of the machine to the application.
将机器与应用程序连接起来。
That's all of the operating system.
这就是操作系统的全部内容。
And just to for big picture of what happens under the hood when you execute
当你执行时，底层发生的大致情况是这样的
a program.
一个程序。
To remember, if you remember,
记住，如果你记得的话，
your copy is a program.
你的副本是一个程序。
It's on the disk that you copy the code in the memory,
它是在将代码从磁盘复制到内存中的过程中发生的。
and then you start executive.
然后你开始执行。
Let's see what happens when you execute.
让我们看看执行时会发生什么。
And here a it's a a snippet of assembly language.
这是一段汇编语言的片段。
And basically, what happens here?
基本上，这里发生了什么？
You allowed some from this address data one,
你允许从这个地址获取一些数据。
the data, which is there and register at one.
数据在一个寄存器中，并且已经注册。
And depending on the value,
根据数值的不同，
you are going to jump to this address.
你将要跳转到这个地址。
Otherwise,
否则，
you are going to decrement the value.
你将要减少这个值。
And then you are going to, look,
然后你要，看，
you go to until it's not zero,
你继续执行直到它不为零。
b and z means r one is not zero.
b和z表示r不为零。
You go back.
你回去。
Basically, as long as it's not,
基本上，只要不是的话，
when it's zero, you jump out of you terminate.
当它为零时，你跳出并终止。
Basically, in this code,
基本上，在这段代码中，
take a piece of data,
获取一段数据，
checks it.
正在检查。
And then you take advantage,
然后你利用这个机会，
and then you go back.
然后你回去。
So what is in memory for this program?
这个程序在内存中有什么内容？
Or do you start?
还是你开始？
So in memory, you have only beats.
在内存中，你只有节拍。
This is an example here.
这是一个例子。
And you have 2 columns for the physical address.
你有两列用于物理地址。
The column on the left are the addresses.
左侧的列是地址。
And the column on the right are the content is the content of the novels.
右侧的栏目是小说的内容。
In this memory layout.
在这个内存布局中。
We are using 4 byte words.
我们使用4字节的字。
How do you see that?
你是怎么看待这个问题的？
You see this number here on the right, 0000.
你看到右边的这个数字，0000。
You have 1234560cents, and20.
你有1234560美分，还有20个。
You have eight characters.
你有八个字符。
Each of these characters,
这些字符中的每一个，
a sorry,
对不起，
represent4bits,
表示4位的数字，
right?
对的？
It's a hexadecimal format.
这是一个十六进制格式。
It's from zero to f each of these is from zero to f we have eight of them,
每个都从零到f，我们有八个。
8times for its 32bits.
对于32位系统来说，这个数字需要重复8次。
They have 32 bits worth,
它们有32位的长度。
or for byte work.
或者适用于字节操作。
The sink with a red are the addresses which also appears in the program.
红色的汇聚点是程序中出现的地址。
You have three addresses,
你有三个地址，
four addresses.
四个地址。
One is the address for this data one.
这个数据的地址是1。
This is red.
这是红色的。
The blue one is check it,
蓝色的那个是检查它。
address the green one.
请处理绿色的那个。
It's a loop.
这是一个循环。
Others now,
其他人现在，
tell me now,
请告诉我现在，
I said that,
我说过，
say, take with the red,
拿红色的。
I said that z zero zero, c zero,
我说的是 z 零 零，c 零。
which is a program,
这是一个程序，
refers to this0300.
指的是这个0300。
Can you figure out how these are connected and why they are connected?
你能弄清楚这些是如何连接的以及为什么它们连接在一起吗？
Why basically the same thing?
为什么基本上是同样的事情？
So here it is.
所以这就是它。
If you address the memory at 32 beats boundaries,
如果您按照32字节边界访问内存，
so an address as the word granularity,
地址的粒度可以理解为以字为单位。
each order is 4bytes.
每个订单占据4个字节。
You need 4 times fewer addresses.
你只需要四分之一的地址。
That's what it is.
就是这样。
That's basically what happens here.
这基本上就是在这里发生的事情。
Right?
对吗？
When the program is going to,
当程序即将执行时，
look, you compile the program.
看，你编译程序。
And when you allocate the memory,
当你分配内存时，
everything happens at forward for the 4bytes,
所有的事情都在前进4个字节的位置发生。
granite or 32 beats granite.
花岗岩或32拍花岗岩。
There are four as this granularity.
这个粒度有四个。
We need 4 times fewer so to speak,
我们需要少4倍，可以这么说。
addresses or beats.
地址或节拍。
This is what happens here.
这是在这里发生的事情。
00, c zero is0300,
00, c zero 是0300。
but is absurdity, rupees, granularity.
但是荒谬、卢比、粒度。
Instead of at the 8 bit or background.
而不是在8位或背景上。
Indeed,
确实，
if you multiply c zero by4,
如果你将c乘以零再乘以4，
you get300.
你得到了300。
Any questions here?
这里有什么问题吗？
The same for the other one.
对于另一个也是一样的。
If you multiply grade zero,
如果你将成绩乘以零，
you are going to get a00.
你将得到A00。
If you multiply 0to42×4,
如果你将0到42乘以4，
you get0908.
你得到了0908。
Now, this is how these values are stored in the physical memories,
现在，这是这些值在物理内存中存储的方式，
another way in another representation.
另一种方式在另一种表达中。
Right?
对吗？
You have the values in these boxes.
这些框中有数值。
And the address is on the side.
地址在侧面。
Now, here is a question.
现在，这里有一个问题。
Say i'm running this program,
假设我正在运行这个程序，
and this program loads into physical memory.
这个程序被加载到物理内存中。
And these addresses, right?
这些地址，对吗？
Because these are the addresses,
因为这些是地址。
maybe in the program on the disk.
可能在磁盘上的程序中。
If I run again this program,
如果我再次运行这个程序，
what will happen?
会发生什么？
But I if I run again this program,
但是如果我再次运行这个程序，
I don't want to load to be loaded exactly in the same place,
我不希望加载在完全相同的位置。
because a different instance of the problem by different data.
因为不同的数据会导致问题的不同实例。
So that's one of the problem we need to solve.
这是我们需要解决的问题之一。
You need this translation.
你需要这个翻译。
So one way to do the translation.
所以一种翻译的方法是：
So instead of I modify these addresses with this nuance,
所以，我不是用这种细微差别修改这些地址，
now,
现在，
all these addresses will not overlap with a previous instance.
所有这些地址都不会与先前的实例重叠。
They are going to not overlap to be non overlapping.
他们将不重叠以保持非重叠状态。
And you are going to be able to load the second time you run
当你第二次运行时，你将能够加载。
the same program at a different address space.
在不同的地址空间中运行相同的程序。
So the two programs now they don't step on each other.
现在这两个程序彼此不会干扰。
So there are many way to possible way to translate.
所以有很多可能的翻译方式。
This is only one possibility.
这只是一种可能性。
So translation can happens at 2times the link time,
翻译可以在链接时间的两倍时间内完成。
when or before in our execution time.
在我们的执行时间中的何时或之前。
I it's compile time, link time, and execution time,
这是编译时间、链接时间和执行时间。
but link or lower time.
但是链接或者更低的时间。
So compile time,
编译时，
it's very hard.
这很困难。
We are not going to talk much about it.
我们不打算多谈这个。
The link and low time.
链接和低延迟时间。
It's we are going to talk briefly,
我们要简要地谈一下。
and then we are going to focus mostly when the translation happened and execution.
然后我们将主要关注翻译和执行的过程。
So before talking about link low time translation,
在讨论链接低时延传输之前，
let's remind ourselves what is the lifetime of a program?
让我们回顾一下程序的生命周期是什么？
You start with the source,
你从源代码开始，
you compile, you get the object modules,
你编译后会得到目标模块。
then you link response possible other modules and libraries,
然后你可以将响应链接到其他模块和库。
and then you load it in the memory.
然后你将它加载到内存中。
And in the process, you are going also to the link with some system,
在这个过程中，你还将与某个系统进行链接。
libraries and some libraries.
库和一些库。
You can actually link them at the run time after you started executive.
在执行程序后，你实际上可以在运行时将它们链接起来。
Okay.
好的。
But here is our previous example.
但是这是我们之前的例子。
Actually, what implicitly done?
实际上，隐式地做了什么？
You modify the addresses before loading to memory.
在加载到内存之前，你需要修改地址。
This is linked load time when you modify the others.
当你修改其他内容时，这是链接加载的时间。
Right?
对吗？
Remember, here,
请记住，在这里，
we said this is our program,
我们说这是我们的程序，
right?
对的？
Maybe this is on the disk.
也许这个在磁盘上。
But when I am cooperating system is going to load this program in memory,
但是当我在操作系统中运行这个程序时，操作系统会将它加载到内存中。
is going to override these addresses that is not going to overlap
将要覆盖这些不会重叠的地址
with other programs,
与其他程序一起，
which are already in the physical amount.
这些已经是实际数量了。
So this is what happens.
所以发生了这样的事情。
Okay?
好的？
Make sense?
有意义吗？
It's any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Now, a little bit of history,
现在，让我们来了解一点历史背景，
again,
再一次，
the earliest operating systems for personal computers were very simple.
个人计算机最早的操作系统非常简单。
You have only one other space,
你只有另外一个空间。
and you have only one application and you got a given time.
你只有一个应用程序，并且你有一个给定的时间。
The application was owning the entire physical address space.
该应用程序拥有整个物理地址空间。
You have the illusion of a dedicated machine,
你拥有一个专用机器的错觉，
because you have a dedicated machine.
因为你有一台专用的机器。
How do you do this?
你是如何做到这一点的？
Now is the next step.
现在是下一步。
If you start to work to run multiple programs,
如果你开始工作来运行多个程序，
you want to run in the same computer.
你想在同一台计算机上运行。
It's again, if the operating system doesn't provide your support,
如果操作系统不提供支持的话，
like you see for translation,
就像你所看到的一样，这是一个翻译任务。
the one way you can do it,
你可以这样做：
like we've just seen,
就像我们刚刚看到的那样，
it's basically translation.
这基本上是翻译工作。
You translate the addresses of the program before you load it to avoid overlapping,
在加载程序之前，你需要将地址进行翻译，以避免重叠。
conflicting with another program.
与另一个程序冲突。
This was a case for early version of the microsoft windows, three,
这是一个关于微软Windows早期版本的案例，版本号为3。
the windows, the early version of the windows.
Windows，Windows的早期版本。
With these things,
有了这些东西，
it's risky.
这很危险。
There is no protection to the buggy code and applicable all applications
这个有缺陷的代码没有任何保护措施，适用于所有应用程序。
here have access to the entire memory.
在这里可以访问整个内存。
One application can read and write the data from another application.
一个应用程序可以读取和写入另一个应用程序的数据。
So it can also crash another application.
所以它也可以导致其他应用程序崩溃。
The next level is to provide protection is still one other space.
下一个层次是提供保护的另一个领域。
Still, the applications are going to be,
尽管如此，应用程序将会是...
the addresses will be overwritten when you went by the louder
当你通过扬声器传递时，地址将被覆盖。
before loading the application,
在加载应用程序之前，
the program to the memory.
将程序加载到内存中。
But now you do have protection.
但是现在你确实有保护措施了。
How do you have protections?
你是如何保护自己的？
Base and bound?
基址和界限？
在计算机操作系统中，基址和界限是一种内存管理技术。基址是指内存块的起始地址，界限是指内存块的大小。通过使用基址和界限，操作系统可以将内存划分为多个独立的区域，每个区域都有自己的基址和界限。
基址和界限的使用可以帮助操作系统实现内存保护和隔离。通过限制每个进程的内存访问范围，可以防止进程越界访问其他进程的内存空间，从而提高系统的安全性和稳定性。
在基址和界限的机制下，当一个进程试图访问超出其界限范围的内存时，操作系统会产生一个异常，从而阻止非法的内存访问。这种机制可以帮助操作系统检测和处理内存访问错误，保护系统的稳定性和可靠性。
总之，基址和界限是一种用于内存管理的技术，通过限制每个进程的内存访问范围，提高系统的安全性和稳定性。
Do you remember about this?
你还记得这件事吗？
We talk about that.
我们谈论过这个。
You have a base and a bound and associated with each application.
每个应用程序都有一个基址和一个边界。
And you make sure that when the applications is going to a access,
你要确保当应用程序要访问时，
a memory,
一块内存
that address is going to be between base and bound.
该地址将位于基址和界限之间。
This was in 31 super computer,
这是在31台超级计算机中的情况。
one of the first super computer.
其中一台最早的超级计算机。
This is what we do.
这是我们所做的。
If like we have address of the program here,
如果我们在这里有程序的地址，
101.
The base you have base is 1000 is bound1100.
你所拥有的基数是1000，上限是1100。
When you address, you are going to check.
当你寻址时，你将进行检查。
Sorry, you are going to check whether it's between100, and110.
抱歉，你需要检查它是否在100和110之间。
If it is, you can access a memory.
如果是这样的话，你可以访问内存。
Otherwise,
否则，
you are going to set for you protect and isolate programs.
你将要设置保护和隔离程序。
But this is requires you to, again,
但这需要你再次
override the addresses of the application before the program,
在程序执行之前覆盖应用程序的地址。
before you load it.
在加载之前。
This is also called relocating louder, a louder,
这也被称为重新定位音量更大的声音。
like that is doing that.
就像那样做。
Rewriting is called relocating louder.
重写被称为重新定位更大声。
Can be very fast.
可以非常快速。
The basin bounds are going to be implemented in harbor.
将在港口实施盆地边界。
And there is its only comparison,
这是它唯一的比较对象，
no addition or nothing can done extremely fast.
没有任何加法或其他操作可以做得非常快。
Okay.
好的。
To summarize, we saw unit programming,
总结一下，我们学习了单元编程。
no protection, one program at a given time,
没有保护机制，一次只能运行一个程序。
multiprogramming, no protection,
多道程序设计，无保护
but you have multiple programs at a given time in the same physical memory.
但是在同一物理内存中，您可以同时运行多个程序。
And you need relocating loader to make sure that the programs,
你需要使用重定位加载器来确保程序可以在内存中正确加载和运行。
when you load them,
当你加载它们时，
you overwrite their addresses so that they don't step on each other.
你覆盖它们的地址，以防它们相互干扰。
Finally, here we have, again,
最后，我们再次来到这里，
no protection,
没有保护
one physical memory,
一个物理内存
no visualization.
没有可视化。
You have also base and bounds to,
你还有基址和界限。
sorry.
对不起。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
again, you have only one address physical memory,
再次强调，你只有一个物理内存地址。
only one other space,
只有另一个空间。
which is shared by the applications.
这是应用程序共享的。
But in this case, you provide protection by using base and bounds.
但在这种情况下，你可以通过使用基址和界限来提供保护。
This is provided in harvard.
这是哈佛提供的。
So now,
所以现在，
it's a time.
现在是时间。
This is a pretty complicated,
这是一个相当复杂的问题。
like relocating louder and so forth.
如重新定位、更大声等等。
It's pretty complicated and it's pretty limited.
这很复杂，而且很有限。
So next,
接下来，
we are going to start discussing about the general address translation.
我们将开始讨论关于通用地址转换的内容。
Okay?
好的？
The general address translation is happening this way.
通常的地址转换是这样进行的。
You have the cpu.
你拥有CPU。
Remember this because sometimes it's little confusion.
记住这个，因为有时候会有一点困惑。
When the cpu issues an instruction.
当CPU发出一条指令时。
In general,
一般来说，
the instructions contain virtual addresses.
这些指令包含虚拟地址。
So these virtual addresses are then mapped to the physical address.
因此，这些虚拟地址随后被映射到物理地址。
And they are done, typically,
通常情况下，它们已经完成了。
by cheap or part of the processor,
通过廉价或处理器的一部分，
which is called mmu memory management unit.
这被称为内存管理单元（MMU）。
The programs,
这些程序，
because they are running on the CPU they see mutual address spaces.
因为它们在CPU上运行，所以它们看到的是共享的地址空间。
Okay?
好的？
From the memory side,
从内存方面来看，
you have only physical addresses.
你只有物理地址。
In translation,
在翻译中，
it's a generalized technique,
这是一种通用技术，
which helps you is many things.
这有很多帮助你的东西。
But if you really want,
但是如果你真的想要的话，
if you only want,
如果你只想要的话，
like I mentioned,
就像我之前提到的那样，
protections,
保护措施，
control, overlap,
控制，重叠
and sing like that.
并且像那样唱歌。
But if you really want to implement only one of these things like protection,
但是如果你真的只想实现其中一件事，比如保护机制，
like you've seen in the past,
就像你过去所见到的那样，
things are easier while you're on protection,
在受到保护的时候，事情会变得更容易。
because if task a cannot gain access to speed data,
因为如果任务A无法访问速度数据，
no way for anr to adversely affect.
ANR（Application Not Responding）无法产生负面影响。
Now,
现在，
if you have the translation,
如果你有翻译的话，可以提供给我。
then every program can be linked or loaded into the same region of the users.
那么每个程序都可以链接或加载到用户的同一区域。
Again, you have two applications.
再次，你有两个应用程序。
In this case.
在这种情况下。
Both applications have different virtual addresses,
这两个应用程序具有不同的虚拟地址。
virtual address space,
虚拟地址空间
because they have their own process.
因为它们有自己的进程。
And each process has its own address space, visual address.
每个进程都有自己的地址空间和虚拟地址。
These boss applications,
这些老板应用程序，
they can see the same virtual memory.
他们可以看到相同的虚拟内存。
Both of them, they see visual memory, say,
他们两个都能看到视觉记忆，比如说，
from 000 to fff the trick here is that these two address spaces are
从000到fff，这里的技巧是这两个地址空间是连续的。
going to be mapped to different locations in the physical memory by using translation.
通过使用转换，将要映射到物理内存的不同位置。
That's what the translation gives.
这是翻译的结果。
Let's consider examples.
让我们来考虑一些例子。
It's a one way to do it.
这是一种方法来做。
It's a very simple change of the previous
这是对之前的一个非常简单的修改。
basin bound technique.
盆地边界技术。
Here is a difference.
这是一个区别。
Let me just go back to make sure that it's different, right?
让我回去确认一下，确保它是不同的，对吗？
This is the difference.
这是不同之处。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
the base and bound,
基址和界限
right?
对的？
Are absolute addresses.
是绝对地址。
And the program address is also absolute address.
程序地址也是绝对地址。
You have 1010,
你有1010个。
and absolute meaning.
绝对含义。
I am referring to physical addresses.
我指的是物理地址。
You need to compare 1010 with the base and with a bound.
你需要将1010与基准值和上限进行比较。
With translation,
翻译如下：
通过翻译，
the program address is not absolute,
程序地址不是绝对的。
is the relative to the bound to the basis.
这个句子的意思不太清楚，可能是有些语法错误。如果你能提供更多的上下文，我可以帮你更好地理解并翻译这个句子。
Actually, the real address,
实际上，真实地址是
physical address is a program address plus the base.
物理地址是程序地址加上基址。
In this case, a program address is 0010.
在这种情况下，程序地址是0010。
Base address is 1000.
基地址是1000。
If you add them up, it's 1010.
如果你把它们加起来，结果是1010。
These addresses are translated on the flight.
这些地址是实时翻译的。
Right?
对吗？
Very convenient.
非常方便。
So you still now,
所以你现在还在吗？
this program addresses,
这个程序解决了...
they don't need to be changed.
它们不需要被改变。
The only thing I need to change in order to make sure that programs
程序确保正常运行的唯一需要更改的事情是
are mapped into different address spaces.
被映射到不同的地址空间中。
Physical address spaces is the just chains of these others.
物理地址空间只是这些其他地址空间的链表。
Right?
对吗？
Indeed,
确实，
right?
对的？
It's harder for location.
定位更困难。
It's also called, then basically,
它也被称为，基本上，
a question here, can you touch the program?
这里有一个问题，你能触碰程序吗？
Can you touch the os but if you are careful,
如果你小心的话，你可以触碰操作系统。
we are not going.
我们不去了。
You cannot touch the os because the os will be outside the base address
你无法访问操作系统，因为操作系统位于基地址之外。
and the bound address of any
和任何绑定地址的
up any user process.
唤醒任何用户进程。
Can you touch other programs?
你能够接触其他程序吗？
Now, if you are careful,
现在，如果你小心的话，
that's how you provide protection.
这就是你提供保护的方式。
Again, it's a very simple idea.
再说一遍，这是一个非常简单的想法。
Any questions about that?
对此有任何问题吗？
Do you see how now I no longer need to override the program analysis?
你看到了吗，现在我不再需要覆盖程序分析了吗？
When I load the program in memory,
当我将程序加载到内存中时，
I just do that as a runner when the program I give.
当我运行给定的程序时，我只是作为一个运行者来执行这个任务。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Okay.
好的。
What are the issues with this basin bound method?
这个盆地边界方法存在哪些问题？
The issue here is about what is called is about fragmentation.
这里的问题是关于所谓的碎片化。
And this is a very simple example,
这是一个非常简单的例子，
because each process requires different amount of data,
因为每个进程需要不同数量的数据，
the different amount of space, memory space.
不同的空间量，内存空间。
They are not uniform,
它们不是统一的。
because they are not uniform,
因为它们不是统一的，
like in this case process to requires a lot.
就像在这种情况下，进程需要很多资源。
And you process to goes away.
然后你的进程消失了。
Another process nine comes,
又来了一个进程九，
you are locates a memory spatial process,
你正在定位一个内存空间的进程。
9+5 goes away.
9+5消失了。
And now look at this situation,
现在看看这种情况，
you have process 11,
你有进程11。
and you have enough physical memory for process 11.
你的物理内存足够容纳进程11。
But the point that this physical memory is scattered and process 11 needs
但是问题是这个物理内存是分散的，进程11需要
a contiguous region of memory.
一个连续的内存区域。
That's a problem.
这是一个问题。
How do you do it?
你是如何做到的？
What is your solution here?
你在这里的解决方案是什么？
There are many solutions.
有很多解决方案。
But one simple solution is to have,
但是一个简单的解决方案是拥有，
instead of only one segment for each program,
每个程序不再只有一个段，
you can have different segments.
你可以拥有不同的段。
Typically, you can have code segment,
通常情况下，你可以有代码段，
data segments that had segment sub segment.
具有段子段的数据段。
You do this independently.
你可以独立完成这个任务。
This gives you a little bit more flexibility.
这会给你更多的灵活性。
Also, another problem is the solution I show you here,
另外，还有一个问题是我在这里展示给你的解决方案。
the original solution, the ban,
原始解决方案，禁止
the basin bound is that remember about threads and processes.
基本原则是要记住线程和进程。
You can have multiple threads in the same process.
在同一个进程中可以有多个线程。
The site is the same process.
该网站是同一个过程。
Here is a code.
这是一段代码。
But how you are going to do it here,
但是你在这里要如何做呢？
right?
对的？
Because right?
因为对吗？
And even like think about, actually,
而且，实际上，甚至还要考虑到，
you can think about maybe a better example than what I said is libraries.
你可以考虑一个比我之前提到的更好的例子，比如图书馆。
If you have common library system libraries with these libraries,
如果你有与这些库相同的常用库系统库，
they are used by multiple applications.
它们被多个应用程序使用。
So it makes no sense to allow the copy of the library for each application
因此，允许每个应用程序复制该库是没有意义的。
set up against share system values.
建立起对共享系统价值的抵制。
Right?
对吗？
How are you doing?
你好吗？
Again,
再次，
now we can alleviate this problem.
现在我们可以缓解这个问题。
Like I mentioned that instead of having one segment per process,
就像我之前提到的，我们不再采用每个进程一个段的方式，
you have multiple segments,
你有多个段落。
right?
对的？
But process a typical one, like I mentioned,
但是处理一个典型的进程，就像我之前提到的那样，
you have code data stacked heap segment.
你有代码段、数据段、堆段和栈段。
But in general, you can have a segment at one extreme.
但一般来说，你可以在一个极端拥有一个段落。
You can have a segment for each function.
你可以为每个函数分配一个段。
Right?
对吗？
For a segment, you have a base and a bound or a limit.
对于一个段，你有一个基址和一个界限或限制。
Now, because the segments are smaller,
现在，由于分段更小，
you have more flexibility how to place them in the physical,
你在物理上放置它们的方式更加灵活。
in the physical memory.
在物理内存中。
Let me go back here in this process 11.
让我回到这个进程的第11步。
If this process 11,
如果这个进程是11，
maybe it had been consisted by from two segments.
可能它由两个片段组成。
Then you'd have feet.
那么你就会有脚。
You could have feet.
你可以有脚。
Process one in physical memory,
物理内存中的进程一。
because maybe one segment of process one would have fit in one of these gaps,
因为进程一的某个段可能适合填补这些间隙之一，
and the other one is the other gap.
另一个是另一个间隙。
So that's how multiple segments can help.
这就是多个段可以帮助的原因。
This is one version.
这是一个版本。
You have then a map.
你现在有一张地图。
How would you implement it?
你会如何实现它？
Now you need a map,
现在你需要一张地图，
a segment map,
一个段映射表
which needs to reside in the processor.
需要驻留在处理器中。
And then how do you address it?
然后你如何解决这个问题？
How do we know we segment?
我们如何知道我们正在进行分段操作？
We are in.
我们进来了。
So one way to do it is to divide the address space,
所以一种方法是将地址空间划分为多个部分，
a virtual address into two.
将一个虚拟地址分成两部分。
The first beats of the asset advice are the most significant ones represent the
资产建议的首要节拍是最重要的，代表着
segment.to this segment map.
将此段映射到该段位图中。
And the second and the other part of the address is a quality of.
地址的第二部分和其他部分是一个质量的。
So when the processor issues such virtual address,
当处理器发出这样的虚拟地址时，
the processor take the first,
处理器取第一个。
the segment beats its indexes in the segment map,
段在段映射中击败了它的索引。
then it gets the base and the limit the offset is added to the base.
然后它获取基址和限制，将偏移量添加到基址上。
And now this you have the physical address,
现在你已经有了物理地址，
and then you need also to compare the offset to the limit,
然后你还需要将偏移量与限制值进行比较，
right?
对的？
To see that you are within the segment.
确认你在该段内。
If not, it's an error.
如果不是，那就是一个错误。
You are done.
你完成了。
Now you can chunk the memory in as many chunks that you have
现在你可以将内存分成与你拥有的块数相同的块。
in this map map table.
在这个映射表中。
And this is what very early versions of intel 86
这是Intel 86的早期版本。
are implemented.
已经实现。
86.
86可以翻译成中文为八十六。
We are going to stop here.
我们要停下来了。
We are at time.
我们现在是在时间上。
And we are going to continue our discussion on virtual memory.
我们将继续讨论虚拟内存的问题。
Next Monday.
下周一。
Until then, good luck with project two is good to start early.
在那之前，祝你在项目二中好运，早点开始是个好主意。
I'll see you then on virtually.
那么我们就在虚拟平台上见了。
I'll see you on Monday.
我周一见你。
If you have any other questions, please, let me know.
如果你有任何其他问题，请告诉我。